



Core Competencies

- Brand Management
- Marketing Communication
- New Product Launch
- Marketing Campaigns
- . ATL & BTL Activities
- Category Management
- Marketing Strategy
- Offline Marketing
- Online Marketing
- Market Research
- Channel Management
- Trade Marketing
- Loyalty Program Management



Technical Skills

- MvSOL
- Mobile Device Management



Personal Information

Date of birth 15-Aug-1989

Gender Male

City Gurgaon/Gurugram

Country INDIA

Swadhin Das

Category Manager- Product Marketing





swadhin.marketing@gmail.co

"

P&L Owner, Category & Brand Lead at Dalmia Cement (Bharat) Limited



Profile Summary

Experienced Marketer, Instrumental in Leading categories and establishing brands with multifold growth across different industries. Currently I am leading & Owning the P&L of several mass brands at Dalmia Cement and lead their Trade Marketing vertical aiming at higher channel engagement and expansion to new markets.



Education

MBA/PGDM, 2017

Xavier Institute of Management (XIM), Bhuvaneshwar

B.Tech/B.E., 2011

Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT)



Work Experience

Apr 2020 - Apr 2020

Category Manager- Product Marketing

Dalmia Cement (Bharat) Limited

- Owned & Managed the P&L for assigned brands in category and achieved top line targets
 assh month
- Launched and scaled the brand in new markets like Central region and managed the entire GTM in close coordination with different stakeholders.
- Implemented various consumer researches like U&A, Brand Track, CSAT, Brand Equity & Communication Eval for strategic decision making
- Managed branding strategy for the category including ??? GTM, Brand key, Consumer Campaigns, ATL, BTL & Digitalactivities
- Identify Opportunities, Gaps, Strengths and Weakness based on Market insights and launched products in specific territory as per market needs
- Mentoring & monitoring existing product mix as per market requirement in alignment with expected profitability
- Support Sales & Technical Service Team with Sales/Service Tool, Pitching requirement,
 Market Trend data making.
- Conceptualize product roadmap for Trade Marketing vertical through loyalty cum engagement app to drive brand loyalty among channel partners and used analytics to drive sales extraction

Programs/Product Delivered

- Launched new brand ???Dalmia Supreme Cement??? in eastern region and led entire NPD & GTM
- Led new market expansion in Central region ??? Uttar Pradesh & Uttarakhand and set up
 the entire product availability, channel acquisition, Market Visibility initiatives with
 several campaigns like ???Majboot Kal Ka Nirmaan ???Dalmia Cement??? for Outdoor & In
 store, ???Khusiyon ka Naya Rang ??? Dalmia Cement??? for Holi Festival campaign
- Prepared the Brand Positioning strategy for Dalmia Cement by conducting workshops,
 effective usage of concept cards and evaluated through animatics
- Launched Consumer promotion property ????Har Ghar Happy Offer??? to promote brandsand executed the promotion e2e through Whatsapp Chatbot (First time in Industry), ATL & BTL Communication
- Executed an innovative on ground Campaign ???Subh Subh Banao??? using coconut props to drive auspiciousness of building new home with Dalmia Cement in 60+ cities

- connecting more than 20K stakeholders
- Revamped the Channel engagement program ???Dalmia Delight??? from just a point earning platform to a program promoting loyaltycum engagement and support business objectives through sales driven campaigns.
- Received Bronze Award for Dalmia Delight Program at Dragons of Asia in category of ???

 Best Business to Business or Trade Marketing Campaign???
- Launched the Influencer marketing program Dalmia Masters to promote brand advocacy by Masons/Contractors

May 2017 - Apr 2020

Assistant Category Manager - Product Marketing

MRF Tyres

- Category management for Product Group ??? Passenger Car Tyres and built several brands like ZLX, Wanderer, ZTX
- New Product development in coordination with Product Development Team suiting emerging market needs
- Marketing mix planning and launching new products and refreshes forspecialized channels
- Conceptualize product roadmap for Omni channel 2W & Car Tyres retail drive product enhancements for inventory management, pricing and promotions.
- Managing e-commerce division e2e across 11 Major cities in country across product group by defining set parameters, SLA and provide additional business opportunities to existing Premium Channel Partners
- Leading the platform STAMP ??? A Unique Customer Retention Service Program live across 600+ Premium Outlets and thereby building a long term relationship with customer and enhance profitability for partners
- Implemented Mobile Device Management solution through app based program on customized Tabs across 1000 outlets to promote user engagement and drive impact based selling.
- Market research and analysis for strategic decision making

Jan 2012 - Aug 2015

Software Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

- Actively engaged in requirement analysis & gap identification by participating in various client meetings across telecom & banking domain
- Developed an internal application which acted as a Knowledge Bank (logic pool) for all teams across companies working on the projects.
- Designed & Implemented quality assurance strategies for British Telecom (BT) & Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce (CIBC)
- Responsible for developing automation scripts for regression testing of BT Sports application under challenging timelines